（捷克 布拉格）
M并不会介意你额外赚点小钱 赖安
M doesn't mind you earning a little money on the side, Dryden.
她只是希望 不要靠出卖机密来赚钱
She'd just prefer it if it wasn't selling secrets.
如果你是想吓吓我的话
If the theatrics are supposed to scare me…
…邦德 你找错人了
…you have the wrong man, Bond.
如果M真的认为我变节了…
If M was so sure that I was bent…
…她会派00探员来的
…she'd have sent a double-0.
尽管只是区域主管…
Benefits of being section chief…
…我知道所有被晋升为00身份的探员
…I'd know if anyone had been promoted to double-0 status…
…对吗？
…wouldn't I?
- 你的档案显示你没杀过人 而且… - 杀过2个
- Your file shows no kills, and it takes… - Two.
真遗憾
Shame.
我们之间还了解甚少
We barely got to know each other.
我知道你把枪放在哪里
I know where you keep your gun.
所以我还是了解你的
I suppose that's something.
确实是
True.
他是怎么死的？
How did he die?
你的联络人？
Your contact?
死的很惨
Not well.
他叫你感受到了死亡 是吗？
Made you feel it, did he?
嗯…
Well…
…你不用担心
…you needn't worry.
第二个是…
The second is…
是
Yes.
相当对
Considerably.
《007系列之大战皇家赌场》
（乌干达 姆巴莱）
我怎么才能放心把钱交给这个 素未谋面的人呢？
So how do I trust this man that I've never met with my money?
你要求引见
You asked for the introduction.
我的组织只能向你担保这些
That's all my organization will guarantee.
我想我们的朋友 怀特先生已经告诉过你
I suppose our friend Mr. White will have told you…
…这些年来…
…that I have provided reliable banking services…
…我向很多自由战士 提供了可靠的银行服务
…for many other freedom fighters over the years.
你相信上帝吗 拉西福先生？
Do you believe in God, Mr. Le Chiffre?
不
No.
我相信合理的回报率
I believe in a reasonable rate of return.
我不想投资有任何风险
I want no risk in the portfolio.
同意
Agreed.
我能在全球任何一个角落提钱？
And I can access it anywhere in the world?
可以
Yes.
钱到手了 做空一百万…
I have the money, so short another million shares…
…股天空舰的股票
…of Skyfleet stock.
先生 要知道你这可 是在和市场对赌
Sir, you must know you're betting against the market.
大家都一致认为这支股只涨不跌
No one expects this stock to go anywhere but up.
照做就是了
Just do it.
（马达加斯加）
看来我们的朋友 在自己脸上烧了不少伤疤
Looks like our man. Burn scars on his face.
不知道炸弹制造者 能不能给这种事投保
I wonder if bomb-makers are insured for things like that.
他开始行动了
He's on the move.
他开始行动了 他正径直向我走来
He's on the move, and he's heading straight for me.
别摸你的耳朵
Stop touching your ear.
- 你说什么？- 把手放下来
- Sorry? - Put your hand down.
把该死的枪放下 卡特 我要抓活的
Holster the bloody weapon, Carter. I need him alive.
流血泪只不过是泪腺重排的缘故…
Weeping blood comes merely from a derangement of the tear duct…
…亲爱的先生
…my dear general.
跟邪恶可不着边
Nothing sinister.
全押
All in.
我有2对 你有17.4%的机会…
I have two pair, and you have a 17.4 percent chance…
…能赢
…of making your straight.
（英国政府探员杀害手无寸铁的囚犯）
「省略号」什么时候失效？
When does Ellipsis expire?
- 还有不到36小时 我可以… - 不 不用
- We have less than 36 hours. I can… - No. No, no.
就只有这么多时间
That's all the time I have anyway.
叫客人5分钟内离开…
Give our guests five minutes to leave…
…否则把他们丢到船外
…or throw them overboard.
他们究竟觉得自己是什么人
Who the hell do they think they are?
我向首相汇报 他很聪明…
I report to the prime minister, even he's smart enough…
…但他都不具体追究我们的工作
…not to ask me what we do.
为什么我总是遇到一些自以为是的饭桶？
Have you ever seen such a bunch of self-righteous, arse-covering prigs?
他们根本不关心我们在做什么 他们只在乎被拍照的人在干什么
They don't care what we do, they care what we get photographed doing.
邦德怎么会这么愚蠢？
And how the hell could Bond be so stupid?
我给了他00身份 他却拿枪击使馆作为庆祝
I give him double-0 status, he celebrates by shooting an embassy.
他疯了吗？他现在到底在什么地方？
Is the man deranged? And where the hell is he?
要在过去 探员做出这么难堪的事
In the old days, if an agent did something embarrassing…
他一定得要叛逃才行
…he'd have the good sense to defect.
天啊 我真是怀念冷战时期
Christ, I miss the Cold War.
（已发送短消息）
（巴哈马）
（海洋俱乐部）
你可真是厚颜无耻啊
You've got a bloody cheek.
对不起
Sorry.
下回我一定先打掉摄像机
I'll shoot the camera first next time.
或者你自己
Or yourself.
你袭击了一个使馆
You stormed into an embassy.
你侵犯了唯一神圣不可侵犯的…
You violated the only absolutely inviolate rule…
…国际关系准则
…of international relationships.
为什么呢？为了杀一个无名之辈
And why? So you could kill a nobody.
我们是要审问他 而不是杀了他
We wanted to question him, not kill him.
（情报员击毙无武装囚犯）
天啊 你应该运用一下你的判断力
For God's sake. You're supposed to display some kind of judgment.
我这么做了
I did.
我认为世上少一个 炸弹制造者是件好事
I thought one less bomb-maker in the world would be good.
没错 一个制造炸弹的
Exactly. One bomb-maker.
我们正在试图找出 恐怖组织网的资金来源…
We're trying to find out how an entire network of terrorist groups is financed…
…你却给我个造炸弹的
…and you give us one bomb-maker.
很难算全盘情况 是不是？
Hardly the big picture, wouldn't you say?
那人都不是真正的信徒 他只是个雇佣杀手而已
The man isn't even a true believer. He's a gun for hire.
多亏了你那过度发达的扣扳机的手指…
And thanks to your trigger finger…
…现在我们根本无法得知谁雇佣了他 目的为何
…we have no idea who hired him or why.
你究竟是怎么找到我住的地方的？
And how the hell did you find out where I lived?
跟我发现你真实姓名的方法一样
The same way I found out your name.
我以为M只是随机取的一个字母 没想到它代表的是…
I thought "M" was randomly assigned. I had no idea it stood for…
你要是再说一个字 我就杀了你
Utter one more syllable and I'll have you killed.
我就知道不应该这么快就提升你
I knew it was too early to promote you.
我知道00身份的探员寿命都不长…
Well, I understand double-0s have a very short life-expectancy…
…所以你犯的错误也是短暂的
…so your mistake will be short-lived.
邦德 对于一个愚钝的人来说 这些可能难以理解…
Bond, this may be too much for a blunt instrument to understand…
…但是盲目自大和自我意识 几乎不可能协调共存
…but arrogance and self-awareness seldom go hand in hand.
这么说你希望我是半个圣人 半个终极杀手了？
So you want me to be half monk, half hit-man?
任何刺客都可以杀人
Any thug can kill.
我希望你能克服你的自负…
I want you to take your ego out of the equation…
…冷静的分析局势
…and to judge the situation dispassionately.
我必须要确定我可以信任你 而你也清楚信任谁
I have to know I can trust you, and that you know who to trust.
但现在还不能确定 我要你在我眼前消失
And since I don't know that, I need you out of my sight.
找个地方冷静一下
Go and stick your head in the sand somewhere…
…好好考虑一下你的未来
…and think about your future.
这些混蛋现在想要你的命
Because these bastards want your head.
我正严肃考虑 是否把你交出去
And I'm seriously considering feeding you to them.
还有 邦德…
And Bond…
…不要再擅闯我家了
…don't ever break into my house again.
好的
Ma'am.
（巴哈马 拿骚）
你好 先生 欢迎光临海洋俱乐部
Good day, sir, and welcome to the Ocean Club.
你是帮我停车还是让我这么等着？
Are you going to take this or make me wait?
当然 先生 对不起 先生
Certainly, sir. Sorry, sir.
保安去停车场 保安去停车场
Security to car park. Security to car park.
欢迎光临海洋俱乐部 先生 您要入住吗？
Welcome to the Ocean Club, sir. Checking in?
是的 但我这是一时冲动之举 我并没有提前预定
Yes. But it's a spur-of-the-moment thing, and I haven't got a reservation.
- 我们有间面向大海的豪华房 - 太好了
- We have an ocean-view villa. - Perfect.
你能帮我个忙吗？我昨晚在这里进晚餐…
Could you do me a favor? I was here last night…
…我把车停在一辆非常漂亮的 1964年出厂的阿斯顿马丁旁
…and I parked my car next to a very beautiful 1964 Aston Martin.
我把它的车门刮了 你是否知道…
I nicked the door. You wouldn't happen to know…
- 是迪米特雷斯先生的 - 没错
- Mr. Dimitrios. - Right.
如果他本人还没有发现 我觉得这事最好还是不要提
If he hasn't noticed, I'm not sure I'd mention it.
他对坏消息的反应可很强烈呢
Isn't the type to take bad news well.
但是如果我要找他呢？
But if I felt compelled to find him?
他在海边有栋房子
He has a house just up the beach.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 什么事？- 他现在在巴拿马
- What? - He's in the Bahamas.
你把我吵醒就是为了告诉我 他在哪里度假？
You woke me to share his holiday plans?
他使用你的名字和密码
Well, he's logged into our secure website…
登陆到我们的加密网
…using your name and password.
他是怎么知道的？
Well, how the hell does he know these things?
我会尽力找出答案的
Well, I'm doing my best to find out.
- 他现在在查谁？- 阿里克斯·迪米特雷斯
- Who's he looking at? - Alex Dimitrios.
那个混蛋
That slimy bugger.
现在查的是他的同伙…
Now known associates…
拉西福
Le Chiffre.
要些什么吗 先生？
How can I assist you, sir?
晚上好 一大杯奇峰朗姆酒加苏打 谢谢
Good evening. Large Mount Gay with soda, please.
- 瞧 都是些什么事情啊 - 老兄 手气不错啊
- Look what just happened. - Good job, big boy.
是啊
Yeah.
不介意我也玩两把吧？
Do you mind if I join?
- 晚上好 - 晚上好
- Oh, good evening. How are you? - Good evening.
小盲注 大盲注
Small blind, big blind.
我跟
I'm in.
轮到你了
Bet's to you.
如果是来祝我好运的话 你迟到了2小时
If that was for luck, you're two hours late.
2万跟吗？
Two hundred to you.
轮到你了
Bet's to you.
我听到了
I heard you.
5千跟吗？
Five to call.
- 轮到你了 - 一对7
- Action's to you. - Pair of sevens.
一张A
Ace high.
跟牌还是让牌
Check or bet.
- 跟牌 - 轮到你了
- Check. - And to you.
跟进5千
Five thousand.
Five to call.
- 跟牌 - 到你了 先生？
- Check. - Check to you, sir.
全部都押上
All in.
等一下
No, wait.
两万
Twenty thousand.
只限台上的注 对不起 先生
Table stakes. I'm sorry, sir.
好吧 这个在台上 我的车 可以赌吗？
Okay. This is on the table. That's my car. Wanna bet?
对不起 迪米特雷斯先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Dimitrios.
别这样 给他个机会把钱赢回来
Please, no. Give him a chance to win his money back.
请亮牌 先生们
All right, show me, gentlemen.
3张K
Three kings.
天哪
There you go with my night.
3张A
Trip aces.
A赢
Aces win.
哦 停车票也给我
Oh, and the valet ticket.
谢谢
Thank you.
先生
Sir.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢你 先生
- Thank you. - Thank you, sir.
难怪他情绪那么糟
No wonder he was in such a foul mood.
我的错
My mistake.
我能送你回家吗？
Can I give you a lift home?
那他一定会气疯的
That would really send him over the edge.
恐怕我还没有那么残忍
I'm afraid I'm not that cruel.
可能你都生疏了
Well, perhaps you're just out of practice.
可能吧
Perhaps.
到我那喝一杯怎么样？
Well, what about a drink at my place?
你那？
Your place?
- 离这里近吗？- 非常近
- Is it close? - Very.
那只喝一杯
One drink.
晚上好 先生 欢迎回来
Good evening, sir, and welcome back.
欢迎回到我的住处
Welcome to my home.
我不明白为什么这是我的错
I'm having a hard time seeing how this is my fault.
那是你的计划 我只负责给你找人
It's your plan. All I did was get you the man.
那人正在被英国情报局监视
A man who was under surveillance by the British Secret Service.
这让我开始怀疑是否该信任你
Which makes me wonder if I can trust you at all.
那就别信任我 我根本不在乎
Then don't. I couldn't care less.
但是我在乎我的名声
But I do care about my reputation.
我另外给你找能干这活的人
I have someone else willing to do the job.
他只需要知道一些细节
He just needs the particulars…
…和报酬
…and payment.
你喜欢已婚女人 是不是 詹姆斯？
You like married women, don't you, James?
这样事情简单
It keeps things simple.
什么样的人才是坏人呢？
What is it about bad men?
你还是我丈夫？
You, my husband…
我有那么多获得幸福的机会
I had so many chances to be happy…
…很多不错的男人
…so many nice guys.
为什么那些男人不能象你一样呢？
Why can't nice guys be more like you?
因为要是那样的话 他们就是坏人了
Well, because then they'd be bad.
没错
Yes.
但是却会有意思的多
But so much more interesting.
为什么你丈夫是坏人？
What makes your husband a bad man?
我想大概是他的本性吧
His nature, I suppose.
他的工作性质吗？
The nature of his work?
恐怕那是个迷
A mystery, I'm afraid.
我也怕你和我睡觉 就是为了了解他
I'm also afraid you will sleep with me in order to get to him.
恐怕是吧
How afraid?
你现在没有退路了
Not enough to stop.
能问你个私人问题吗？
Can I ask you a personal question?
现在可是好时机啊
Now would seem an appropriate time.
「省略号」对你来说有什么意义吗？
Does "ellipsis" mean anything to you?
我是不是该问问他？
Should I ask him about it?
以后吧
Perhaps later.
好的 亲爱的
Yes, dear?
我坐今晚最后一班飞机去迈阿密
I'm on the last flight tonight to Miami.
不用等我了 我明早回
Don't wait up. I'll be back in the morning.
好吧 我明白了
Okay, I understand.
明天见 再见
See you tomorrow. Bye-bye.
很显然 他现在正在 飞往迈阿密的最后一趟航班上
Apparently he's on the last flight to Miami…
所以你有整晚的时间审问我
…so you have all night to question me.
这样的话
In that case…
我们需要多来点…
…we're gonna need…
来点香槟
…some more champagne.
晚上好 客房服务部
Good evening. Room Service.
晚上好 我想要一瓶冰香槟
Good evening. Can I get a bottle of chilled Bollinger Grand Annee…
还有鱼子酱
…and the beluga caviar?
- 其他配料 酒具之类的也都要吗？- 是的 都要
- With everything? - Yes, with everything.
- 两份吗 先生？- 什么？
- And would that be for two, sir? - What?
- 要两份吗？- 不 只要一份
- For two? - No, for one.
在这里等着
Wait here.
给你 53牌
There you go. Number 53.
冯·哈根斯博士的人体世界 欢迎您
Dr. von Hagens' Body Worlds invites visitors…
来参观人体的运动系统、消化系统
…to observe the body's various locomotive, digestive…
神经系统和动脉系统
…nervous and vascular systems.
先生们 女士们 请大家注意
Please may I have your attention, ladies and gentlemen?
我们现在看到的 是很特别的东西
I believe it is something very special, what we see here.
这是寓教于乐的
This is edutainment.
…栩栩如生的造型…
…fixed in dramatic and athletic poses…
逼真地再现了人体器官的立体结构
… that reveal the true-to-life spatial relationships amongst organs.
喂
Hello.
把你的车停在明显的地方
Do not leave your vehicle unattended.
欢迎来到迈阿密国际机场
Welcome to Miami International Airport.
机场前的路边不允许停车
Curbside parking in front of the terminal is restricted…
- 什么事？- 我是邦德 我要找M
- Yes. - It's Bond. I need her now.
她现在不能被打扰 可以给她带个口信吗？
I'm afraid she can't be disturbed. Can I take a message?
听好 你快点找到她 告诉她打电话给迈阿密机场安全部门
Listen, you go and find her, tell her to call Security at Miami Airport…
因为我认为这里会有炸弹爆炸 你现在就去找她
…because I think a bomb is about to go off. Do it now.
- 抱歉 请稍等 - 我想你可以办到
- Sorry, can I put you on hold? - I thought you might.
邦德？你现在究竟是要干什么？
Bond? What the hell are you up to?
我一会给你打过来
I'll call you back.
- 天空舰570原型机 - 它怎么了？
- The Skyfleet S570 prototype. - What about it?
世界上最大的飞机 今天将于迈阿密机场公诸于众
"The largest airplane in the world will be unveiled today at Miami Airport."
哦 天哪！
Oh, my God!
邦德？邦德！
Bond? Bond!
他的目标是天空舰570型
His target is the Skyfleet prototype.
它将于今天试飞
It's launching today.
我得走了
I gotta go.
停车！停车！
Stop! Stop!
走！快走！快走！
Get moving! Let's go, let's go, let's go!
空头失效了 很抱歉 我不清楚你究竟损失了多少
The puts expired. I'm sorry, I'm not sure yet how much you've lost.
一亿零一百二十万六千美元
One hundred and one million, two hundred and six thousand dollars.
有人告密
Someone talked.
- 你找到了你想找的了？- 是的 找到了
- You got everything you need? - Yeah, I have.
我要照些相
I'm gonna get a few more photos…
为什么尸体会浮肿？
Quite the body count you're stacking up.
她一定是先被折磨过 你已经杀了她丈夫
She was tortured first. As you'd already killed her husband…
…我们现在没人审问
…she must have been the only one left to question.
她知道你的底细吗？
Did she know anything that could compromise you?
不知道
No.
- 你的真实姓名和意图呢？- 不知道
- Not your name, what you were after? - No.
迪米特雷斯是个中间商
Dimitrios worked as a middleman.
总能获取武器
Knew where to put his hands on weapons…
也能找到买家
…and people who could use them.
谁有钱就给谁干
He worked with anyone who had money.
多年来和一个叫拉西福的人 关系甚为密切
For years he was involved with a man we knew as Le Chiffre…
此人是世界各地恐怖组织背后的银行家
…a private banker to the world's terrorists.
为恐怖分子投资洗钱 他们可以随意提取
He invested their money, gave them access to it wherever they wanted.
太好了 你来了
Oh, good. You're here.
此人是阿尔巴尼亚人 国际象棋高手
Albanian, we believe. Chess prodigy.
数学天才 喜欢用打牌来证明这一点
A bit of a mathematical genius and liked to prove it by playing poker.
想监视我？
So you can keep an eye on me?
是的
Yes.
专家在911之后分析股市时
When they analyzed the stock market after 9/11…
美国中情局发现有人 大做航空公司股票的空头
…the ClA discovered a massive shorting of airline stocks.
9月12日当股市跌到谷底时有人发了笔大财
When the stocks hit bottom on 9/12, somebody made a fortune.
今早同样的事本应该发生在…
The same thing happened this morning with Skyfleet stock…
…天空舰的股票上
…or was supposed to.
如果原型机被摧毁 公司将会破产
With their prototype destroyed, the company would be near bankruptcy.
然而 有人却因押错而损失过亿
Instead, somebody lost over $100 million betting the wrong way.
你认为是这个叫拉西福的人
You think it's this man Le Chiffre.
这也解释了他为什么要在
Which would explain how he could set up a high-stakes poker game…
黑山的皇家赌场开高额赌局
…at Casino Royale in Montenegro.
10位玩家 每人赌注1千万 可以再买注5百万
Ten players, $10 million buy-in, 5 million re-buy.
赢家全拿 赌金可能高达1亿5千万
Winner takes all. Potentially 150 million.
好啊 这样我们就找到他的行踪了
Good. Then we'll know where he'll be.
要利索地宰了他呢 还只是给他个警告？
Do you want a clean kill or to send a message?
我们要他活着 拉西福没有一亿美元去输
We want him alive. Le Chiffre doesn't have 100 million to lose.
那他是在用客户的钱玩股票吗？
Has he been playing the stock market with his clients' funds?
客户知道钱没了 一定会大怒
They're not gonna be too happy when they find out it's gone.
我们不能让他赢这场赌局
We can't let him win this game.
如果输了 他就没处可逃了
If he loses, he'll have nowhere to run.
我们给他提供避难所 换取他知道的一切
We'll give him sanctuary in return for everything he knows.
我决定让你去赌
I'm putting you in the game…
替换罪犯辛迪加组织的人
…replacing someone who's playing for a syndicate.
听薇丽说你是队伍中最厉害的
According to Villiers, you're the best player in the Service.
相信我 我也不希望如此
Trust me, I wish it wasn't the case.
我想问你是否能不动感情
I would ask you if you could remain emotionally detached…
但看起来这对你来说不是问题 是吧 邦德？
…but I don't think that's your problem, is it, Bond?
对
No.
不用担心联系总部
Don't worry about keeping in touch.
我们知道你在哪里
We'll know where you are.
你不用装了
You can stop pretending.
你知道我不会把它丢掉的 不是吗？
You knew I wouldn't let this drop, didn't you?
但我知道你就是你
Well, I knew you were you.
（黑山）
谢谢
Thank you.
我就是钱
I'm the money.
你完全值
Every penny of it.
财政部决定资助你参加赌局
The Treasury has agreed to stake you in the game.
「黄昏」
"Vesper."
我倒是希望 你把钱给你父母
Well, I do hope you gave your parents hell for that.
谢谢
Thank you.
你上司一定人脉深厚
Your boss must be well-connected.
我从未见过这么多钱 轻而易举就批了
I've never seen so much go out the door so quickly.
从未批得如此有型
Or quite so stylishly.
那钱在哪呢？
May I ask you where it is?
一千万已经电汇到你在黑山的账户里了
Ten million was wired to your account in Montenegro…
还有5百万的后备金 如果我认为投资值得
…with a contingency for 5 more if I deem it a prudent investment.
我猜你一定也想到过如果你输了
I suppose you've given some thought to the notion that if you lose…
政府就是在直接给恐怖组织提供资金
…our government will have directly financed terrorism.
有什么好吃的？
What looks good?
那么你说这是概率与赔率
So you're telling me it's a matter of probability and odds.
我还担心运气的问题呢
I was worried there was some chance involved.
你什么时候见过牌最好的人赢呢
Well, only if you assume the player with the best hand wins.
噢 那就是你们所说的「诈牌」
So that would be what you call "bluffing"?
原来你听说过这个词
You've heard the term.
那你应该知道你玩的并不是牌
Then you'll also know that in poker you never play your hand.
而是玩你桌对面的对手
You play the man across from you.
- 而你很会看透人 - 是的 我能
- And you're good at reading people? - Yes, I am.
所以我能从你的言语中
Which is why I've been able to detect…
听出暗藏的讽刺
…an undercurrent of sarcasm in your voice.
钱在你手里我可不放心
I'm now assured our money is in good hands.
你对这个计划并不看好 是不是？
You don't think this is a very good plan, do you?
噢 原来你还有个计划
So there is a plan?
我还以为你把百万金钱
I got the impression we were risking millions of dollars…
成百人命 在赌桌上孤注一掷
…and hundreds of lives on a game of luck.
你还有什么高见呢？邦德先生？
What else can you surmise, Mr. Bond?
针对你的吗 林德小姐？
About you, Miss Lynd?
你的美貌是个问题
Well, your beauty's a problem.
你怕他人对你不重视
You worry you won't be taken seriously.
人们都认为：美女无脑
Which one can say of any attractive woman with half a brain.
没错 但你特意…
True, but this one overcompensates…
…着装男性化…
…by wearing slightly masculine clothing…
比其他女同事更咄咄逼人
…being more aggressive than her female colleagues…
让人难以接受
…which gives her a somewhat prickly demeanor…
好笑的是 这同时也意味着
…and ironically enough, makes it less likely for her to be accepted…
她难以被男上司赏识及提拔
…and promoted by her male superiors…
把她的危机感误认为傲慢
…who mistake her insecurities for arrogance.
我一般会猜你是独生女
Now, I'd have normally gone with only child…
但你对讽刺你父母的话毫无反应
…but, you see, by the way you ignored the quip about your parents…
我猜你只能是个孤儿
…I'm gonna have to go with orphan.
那好
All right.
看你衣着 你去了牛津之类的学校
By the cut of your suit, you went to Oxford or wherever…
还认为是人就应该这么穿着
…and actually think human beings dress like that.
但你如此蔑视衣着
But you wear it with such disdain…
说明你家中并没钱
…my guess is you didn't come from money…
你的同学从未让你忘记这一点
…and your school friends never let you forget it.
如此说来 你上学的钱…
Which means you were at that school by the grace…
…必是受他人恩惠
…of someone else's charity, hence the chip on your shoulder.
所以你非常忌讳 你先猜我是个孤儿
And since your first thought about me ran to orphan…
恰恰说明你才是孤儿出身
…that's what I'd say you are.
是的 你是
Oh, you are.
我很喜欢推测
I like this poker thing.
也合情合理
And that makes perfect sense…
当英国军情6处看中你 这样不经事的年轻人
…since Ml6 looks for maladjusted young men…
可以无视他人性命
…that give little thought to sacrificing others…
保护祖国和女王
…in order to protect Queen and country.
你知道的
You know…
前特别空勤团成员 笑容满面 腕带名表
…former SAS types with easy smiles and expensive watches.
- 劳力士？- 欧米加
- Rolex? - Omega.
漂亮
Beautiful.
我们刚刚认识
Now, having just met you…
所以我不会就冒然说你是 一个冷酷的杂种
…I wouldn't go as far as calling you a cold-hearted bastard.
当然不应该
No, of course not.
不过也不难想象
But it wouldn't be a stretch to imagine.
你视女人为可抛弃的玩物
You think of women as disposable pleasures…
而非实际追求的目标
…rather than meaningful pursuits.
虽然你风度翩翩 邦德先生
So as charming as you are, Mr. Bond…
我会牢牢看好我国政府的钱
…I will be keeping my eye on our government's money…
而不会去注意你丰满的臀部
…and off your perfectly formed arse.
你注意到了？
You noticed?
就算会计也是有想象力的
Even accountants have imagination.
你的羊肉味道如何？
How was your lamb?
走味了
Skewered.
让人心痛
One sympathizes.
晚安 邦德先生
Good evening, Mr. Bond.
晚安 林德小姐
Good evening, Miss Lynd.
- 去华美饭店吗？先生 - 是的
- Hotel Splendid, sir? - That's right.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢
- Thank you, sir. - Thank you.
只是些最后的细节
It's just last-minute details.
看起来 我们深深相爱
Apparently we're very much in love.
你平时都是让服务生 来告诉你这些事情吗？
Do you usually leave it to porters to tell you this sort of thing?
只有当爱情必须短暂时
Only when the romance has been necessarily brief.
我是达林顿·比奇 专业赌徒
I'm Mr. Arlington Beech, professional gambler…
你是斯黛夫尼·波切斯特
…and you're Miss Stephanie Broadchest.
- 我不当 - 这方面你得相信我
- I am not. - You're gonna have to trust me on this.
不 不 我不要
Oh, no, I don't.
我们相爱已久
We've been involved for quite a while…
这次共用一间套房
…hence the shared suite.
我家里人都是严格的罗马天主教徒
But my family is strict Roman Catholic…
为掩人耳目 我们该要间双卧室套房
…so for appearances' sake, it'll be a two-bedroom suite.
我实在讨厌宗教给我们制造隔阂
I do hate it when religion comes between us.
宗教还有紧锁的门
Religion and a securely locked door.
你对此不会有意见吧 邦德？
Am I going to have a problem with you, Bond?
没 不用担心 你根本不合我的口味
No, don't worry. You're not my type.
是太聪明了？
Smart?
是单身
Single.
欢迎光临华美饭店 您贵姓
Welcome to the Hotel Splendid. Your name, sir?
詹姆斯·邦德 是用比奇的名字预定的
James Bond. You'll find the reservation under Beech.
- 欢迎您 邦德先生 - 你来签字 亲爱的
- Welcome, Mr. Bond. - You sign that, dear.
你代表财政部嘛
You represent the Treasury.
谢谢 祝您住得愉快
Thank you. Enjoy your stay.
我会的 谢了
I will. Thank you.
你还真逗
Very funny.
如果拉西福真的消息灵通
Look, if Le Chiffre is that well-connected…
他当然知道我是什么人 也知道钱的来路
…he knows who I am and where the money's from.
但他仍坚持和我赌
Which means he's decided to play me anyway.
要么是他走投无路 要么是他狂妄自大
So he's either desperate or he's overly confident…
无论原因何在 都有助于我了解他
…but either way, that tells me something about him.
而他所得到的不过是 个早已知道的名字而已
And all he gets in return is a name he already has.
现在他倒是对你有些了解
And now he knows something about you.
你做事不择手段
He knows you're reckless.
等下一部
Take the next one.
这里装不下我和你的自我膨胀
There isn't enough room for me and your ego.
邦德先生吗？
Mr. Bond?
- 这是您的 - 谢谢
- It was left for you. - Thank you.
我也爱你 M
I love you too, M.
我叫马西斯 林尼·马西斯 是你们这里的接头人
My name is Mathis. Rene Mathis. I'm your contact here.
他知道我们在监视他么？
Does he know we've been watching him?
拉西福？不可能
Le Chiffre? I don't think so.
因为只有「我」 而不是「我们」
Probably because there's no "we." Just me.
小心点 如果你们惹祸上身
I'm afraid if you get into trouble here…
这附近可没有救兵
…the cavalry won't be coming over the nearest hill.
拉西福昨天刚到
Le Chiffre arrived yesterday…
正在重建关系网
…and spent the time reestablishing old relationships.
警察局长和他现在走的很近
The chief of police and he are now quite close.
就是那个小胡子
That's him, with the mustache.
我左肩这边
Over my left shoulder.
如此说来很棘手
Well, that could make life quite difficult.
是的 但不会很久的
Yeah, and quite possibly shorter.
他是个贪财的人
He's not a very subtle man.
我也试图收买他
I thought about trying to buy his services, but we frankly…
但出价不如拉西福高
…couldn't afford to outbid Le Chiffre.
恕我直言
I hate to say it…
如今是些会计在管理英国军情6处
…but the accountants seem to be running Ml6 these days.
我对会计并无偏见
Oh, not that I have anything against accountants.
很多会计都很可爱
Many of them are lovely people.
所以我决定省一点
So I decided that it was cheaper to supply his deputy…
把他收受贿赂的证据交给副局长
…with evidence that we were bribing the chief.
现在的图像软件真是无所不能啊
It's amazing what you can do with Photoshop these days, isn't it?
你的进步也不小啊 邦德先生
I think your odds are improving, Mr. Bond.
什么？
Yes?
给你的
For you.
你指望我穿这个么？
Something you expect me to wear?
你得打扮得光彩照人
I need you looking fabulous.
当你走到我身后 轻吻我的脖子时
So when you walk up behind me and kiss me on the neck…
对手们只会注意你纤细柔美的颈部曲线
…the players will be thinking about your neckline…
而不是他们手中的牌
…and not about their cards.
你能帮我这个忙么？
Do you think you can do that for me?
我会尽力
I'll do my best.
谢谢
Thank you.
我已经有晚礼服了
I have a dinner jacket.
但是有平常的晚礼服 和特别的晚礼服之分
There are dinner jackets and dinner jackets.
这件是后者
This is the latter.
你得看起来像够格上桌的人
And I need you looking like a man who belongs at that table.
你怎么…
How…
这是手工缝制的
It's tailored.
一见面时就知道你的尺寸了
I sized you up the moment we met.
- 晚上好 先生 - 晚上好
- Good evening, sir. - Good evening.
谢谢
Thank you.
您是代替布利斯特先生吧
And you must be Mr. Bliss' replacement.
欢迎 比奇先生
Welcome, Mr. Beech.
还是邦德呢？我有点糊涂
Or is that Bond? I'm a little confused.
我们可不希望那样 不是吗？
Well, we wouldn't want that, would we?
孟德尔先生 这边请
Monsieur Mendel, way please.
女士们 先生们 欢迎您们的到来
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome.
如你们所知 我们将要玩的是德州扑克
As you know, the game is no-limit hold 'em poker.
每人2张底牌 5张公共牌
Five communal cards, two in the hole.
孟德尔先生代表瑞士巴塞尔银行
Monsieur Mendel here represents the Basel Bank, Switzerland…
保管赌金
…holding the stakes.
女士们 先生们
You have each deposited $10 million buy-in.
你们每人已存入1千万赌注
A further buy-in of 5 million can be made by electronic transfer.
可再电汇赌注5百万
The money will remain in escrow until I return…
赌注会由本行保管
…and the winner of the contest enters his or her password…
直到赌局赢家 在加密机内输入密码
…into the encryptor…
此时全部赌金将会
…whereupon the entire sum will be wired…
电汇到您指定的世界上任何一个账户
…to any bank account in the world you nominate.
邦德先生
Mr. Bond?
我们按字母顺序来
We proceed alphabetically.
请您上前输入您的密码
Please be so kind as to enter a password of your choice.
至少6个字母
Six letters or more.
由套牌来决定发牌顺序
High card for dealer position.
加亚多先生
It's Signor Gallardo.
甘米尔斯基先生下小盲注 5千美元
Mr. Kaminofsky is the small blind, $5000…
福津先生下大盲注 1万美元
…and Mr. Fukutu, the big blind, $10, 000.
各位请尽兴
Well, enjoy the game.
还有4位玩家
Four players.
该您下注
It's your bet.
让牌
Check.
押注 50万
Bet. Fifty thousand.
跟进
Call.
收牌
Fold.
收牌 单挑
Fold. Heads up.
拉西福先生？
Monsieur Le Chiffre.
押注10万
Bet. One hundred thousand.
为什么要在众人瞩目时登场？
Weren't you supposed to enter so the others could see you?
噢 是么？抱歉
Was l? Forgive me.
祝你好运 亲爱的
Good luck, darling.
该您了 邦德先生
It's up to you, Monsieur Bond.
邦德先生？
Monsieur Bond?
抱歉 赌注是多少？10万？
Oh, I'm sorry. What was the bet? A hundred thousand?
跟进
Call.
你好
Hello.
你看上去真是太美丽动人了
I suppose I don't have to tell you how beautiful you look.
赌桌上一半的人都还盯着你看呢
Half the people at that table are still watching you.
香槟
Champagne.
拉西福先生
Monsieur Le Chiffre.
押注20万
Bet. Two hundred thousand.
先生 有人跟进了 请亮牌
Monsieur, you have been called. Showdown, please.
拉西福先生 满堂红 三个2 两个9
A full house to Monsieur Le Chiffre. Deuces full of nines.
邦德先生？
Mr. Bond?
收牌
Fold.
请叫一下吧台服务生
Send the barman over, please.
- 一杯干马提尼 - 好的 先生
- A dry martini. - Wait.
等等 3份哥顿琴酒 1份伏特加
Three measures Gordon's, one of vodka…
半份莉兰开胃酒加冰摇匀
…half of Kina Lillet, shake it over ice…
- 加条薄柠檬皮调味 - 好的 先生
- …then add a thin slice of lemon peel. - Yes, sir.
- 喂 给我也来一杯 - 那我也要一杯
- You know, I'll have one of those. - So will l.
好的
Certainly.
朋友 也给我来一杯吧 柠檬就省了
My friend, bring me one as well. Keep the fruit.
完事了吗？
That's it?
现在大家都可以静下来打牌了吗？
Anyone want to play poker now?
看来有人很心急啊
Someone's in a hurry.
抱歉
Would you excuse me?
你很可口
You taste nice.
- 我们不是已经不要伪装了吗？- 错了
- I thought we dispensed with covers. - No.
没用的伪装当然丢掉 我们现在创造有用的
We dispensed with one that was of no use and created another that is.
- 他在看么？- 是的
- Is he watching? - Yes.
很好
Good.
我扮演的角色很生气 因为你输得这么快
This is me in character pissed off because you're losing so fast…
恐怕难过午夜
…we won't be here past midnight.
奇怪的是我和我的角色有同感
Oddly, my character's feelings mirror my own.
让牌
Check.
- 味道还真是不错 - 该您了
- You know, that's not half bad. - Up to you.
我得给它想个名字
I'm gonna have to think up a name for that.
花点钱探出他的马脚绝对值得
It was worth it to discover his tell.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
他诈牌时左眼轻微抽搐 他会用手遮挡
The twitch he has to hide when he bluffs.
- 诈牌？他手里的牌是最大 - 他最后才拿到的
- Bluffs? He had the best hand. - Which he got on the last card.
几率是23比1 他当然知道
The odds against were 23-to-1, and he'd know that.
他第一次加注时 什么牌都没有
When he did his first raise he had nothing.
不过运气罢了
Winning was blind luck.
- 带了监听器吗？- 是的
- Did you get the bug? - Yes.
下注10万
Bet. One hundred thousand.
谢谢
Thank you.
到您了 福津先生
It's your play, Monsieur Fukutu.
说不定他真的能赢
Maybe he can actually pull this off.
跟进
Call.
拉西福先生
Monsieur Le Chiffre.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen, Mesdames, Messieurs…
赌局已经进行了4个小时
…we've now been playing for four hours.
现在休息片刻 一个小时后继续
It's time for a short break. We will resume play in one hour.
我会报告今晚的进程
Well, I think I'll report on the evening's frivolities.
怎么样？
So?
你让他监视我？
You want to do what to me?
我完全不懂你的意思
You've lost me completely.
你不是刚说迫不及待要和我回房么 跟我来
You just said you can't wait to get me back to the room. Come on.
到底什么事这么重要？
So, what's so damn important?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我的钱呢？
Where is my money?
- 晚上好 - 晚上好
- Good evening. - Good evening.
我要拿我的包裹
You're holding a parcel for me.
谢谢
Thank you.
你以为损失了那么多钱 没有人会发现？
Do you think you can lose that kind of money and no one would notice?
你们的钱我会还的
Your money is safe.
打开它
Open that.
我明天就能还给你
You'll have it tomorrow.
分文不少
All of it.
你骗我的代价是一只手 不过你还需要它来玩牌
I would take a hand for this betrayal, but you need it to play cards.
伸开手臂
Hold out your arm.
伸开手臂 美人
Hold out your arm, my beauty…
不然就砍你的头
…or I will take your head.
快回房 在那里等我
Go to the room. Wait for me there.
楼梯
Stairs.
居然连句抗议都没有
Not a word of protest.
你该换男朋友了
You should find a new boyfriend.
去找马西斯
Go find Mathis.
告诉他我把尸体藏在这里 让他把尸体处理掉
Tell him I've hidden the bodies here and I want him to get rid of them.
快去 快啊 快去！
Do that now. Go. Go, go!
你换了件衬衫 邦德先生
You changed your shirt, Mr. Bond.
这种小游戏不会让你出大汗淋漓吧
I hope our little game isn't causing you to perspire.
一点点
A little.
除非我开始流血泪 不然不算什么
But I won't consider myself to be in trouble until I start weeping blood.
女士们 先生们 如果大家都准备好了 就继续吧
Ladies and gentlemen, if everybody's ready, let's continue the game.
我觉得我手染鲜血 怎么洗都洗不下去
It's like there's blood on my hands. It's not coming off.
让我看看
Here, let's see.
好点了吧？
That's better.
冷么？
You cold?
是的
Yeah.
过来
Here.
尸体有问题么？
You have any trouble with the bodies?
让我来看看吧
Less than some.
死人一样有用途
Being dead doesn't mean one can't still be helpful.
拉西福以后会诚惶诚恐
That'll keep Le Chiffre looking over his shoulder.
担心还有谁在背地里算计他
He'll be wondering who's gonna come for him next.
姑娘怎么样了？
How's our girl?
把你冰冷的心融化了么？
Melted your cold heart yet?
跟进
Call.
收牌
Fold.
跟进
And call.
还有3位玩家
Three players.
30万
Three hundred grand.
押注30万
Bet. Three hundred thousand.
跟进
Call.
And call.
还有3位玩家
Three players.
让牌
Check.
邦德先生
Monsieur Bond?
押注50万
Bet. Five hundred thousand.
看啊 他露出了马脚
Look. It's the tell. He is bluffing.
老天啊 詹姆斯说的没错
My God, James was right.
该您了
It's up to you.
加注 1百万
Raise. One million.
看来有人知道其中奥妙
Seems someone knows something I don't.
收牌
Fold.
单挑 先生们
Heads up, gentlemen.
该您了
It's up to you.
2百万
Two.
再加注 2百万
Re-raise. Two million.
该您了
And it's up to you.
我全押
I'm all in.
4千零50万
Well, it's 14 million and 500, 000.
该您了 邦德先生
It's up to you, Monsieur Bond.
邦德必须全押 才能破他的诈牌
Bond will have to go all in to call his bluff.
- 跟进 - 跟进
- Call. - Call.
先生们 请摊牌
Gentlemen, showdown, please.
满堂红 3个K和2个A
Full house. Kings and aces.
拉西福先生
Monsieur Le Chiffre.
4个J 拉西福先生胜出
It's four jacks. Monsieur Le Chiffre wins.
你以为我在诈牌 邦德先生
You must have thought I was bluffing, Mr. Bond.
请注意
Please.
我们现在休息一小时
We will now break for one hour.
当我们继续时 大盲注增加为20万
When we return, the big blind will be 200, 000.
很精彩
Good game.
我需要5百万重新入局
Well, I'm gonna need the other 5 million to buy back in.
我不能给你 詹姆斯
I can't do that, James.
听着 我犯了错
Look, I made a mistake.
也许因为没耐心 也许是太轻敌 但我一定能打败他
I was impatient, maybe I was arrogant, but I can beat him.
- 抱歉 - 抱歉？
- I'm sorry. - Sorry?
抱歉？
Sorry?
那还不如说
Try putting that in a sentence.
“抱歉 拉西福赢了
"Sorry Le Chiffre's gonna win…
继续给恐怖分子提供经费 屠杀无辜百姓” 那种“抱歉”？
continue funding terror and killing." That kind of sorry?
你输光是因为你太自负 要我说
You lost because of your ego, and that same ego can't take it.
你不过想挽回面子罢了
That's what this is about.
这样下去 你只能输更多
All you're going to do now is lose more.
你真蠢
Then you're an idiot.
- 你说什么？- 我说你愚蠢透顶
- I'm sorry? - I said, you're a bloody idiot.
看着我
Look in my eyes.
我能打败他 你是知道的
I can beat this man, you know that.
放手
Get your hand off my arm.
伏特加混马提尼
Vodka martini.
- 摇匀还是搅拌的？- 你看我他妈的在乎么？
- Shaken or stirred? - Do I look like I give a damn?
- 詹姆斯 - 带那姑娘走
- James. - Get the girl out.
真是场离奇的赌局 不是吗？
Funny game, right?
都是兄弟 早就应该自我介绍了
Sorry, I should've introduced myself, seeing as we're related.
菲力克斯·莱特 美国中情局的弟兄
Felix Leiter, a brother from Langley.
你要有点信心
You should have a little faith.
我认为你要头脑清醒才能打败他
If you keep your head about you, I think you have him.
曾经能 对不起
Had. Excuse me.
你不再买赌注了么？
You're not buying in?
不买了
No.
听我说 我输地很快 恐怕坚持不了多久
Listen, I'm bleeding chips. I'm not gonna last much longer.
你赢的机会比我大 我来资助你
You have a better chance. I'll stake you.
我是说我给你钱让你能继续赌
I'm saying I'll give you the money to keep going.
不过有个条件 如果你赢了 要由美国中情局逮捕他
Just one thing. If you pull it off, the ClA bring him in.
那赢的钱呢？
And what about the winnings?
你觉得我们缺钱吗？
Does it look like we need the money?
要盲注么？
Shall we up the blinds?
为什么不？
Why not?
押注
Bet.
加注
Raise.
收牌
And fold.
抱歉
Excuse me, please.
跟进
Call.
加注
Raise.
加注50万
Raise. Five hundred thousand.
- 收牌 - 谢谢
- Fold. - Thank you.
收牌
Fold.
谢谢
Thank you.
胜出
Wins.
不好意思
Deal me out.
对不起 先生 您要下大盲注
Sorry, sir. You are the big blind.
请下小盲注
Small blind, please.
- 是谁？- 007
- Who is it? - It's 007.
邦德被下毒了 马上就要心脏停跳
Bond's been poisoned. He's going into cardiac arrest.
保持冷静 不要打断我
Stay calm and don't interrupt. Because you'll be dead…
如果你不照我说的做 你两分钟内就会死
…within two minutes unless you do exactly what I tell you.
全听你的
I'm all ears.
从箱中拿出除颤器
Remove the defibrillator from the pouch.
- 知道是什么毒吗？- 还在扫描
- Do we know what it is yet? - We're still scanning.
将探头贴到你胸口
Attach the leads to your chest.
室性心动过速 是毛地黄制剂
Ventricular tachycardia. Digitalis.
我们能提供什么该给他？工具箱里有安非他明 抗组胺药
What do we give him? The kit has amphetamines, antihistamines…
氢化可的松 还是肾上腺素？
…hydrocortisone. Adrenalin?
- 等它充电完成… - 可以用利多卡因
- As soon as it reads charged… - Lidocaine. That'll work.
邦德 先不要按红钮 听到了吗？不要按红钮
Bond, don't push the red button yet. Do you hear me? Don't push it.
他心脏要停跳了
His heart's gonna stop.
他只够时间做一次电击
There's only time for one charge before he passes out.
邦德 用蓝色多用笔 脖子中间 轧入血管
Take the blue combipen, Bond. Mid-neck into the vein.
有助于解毒
That'll counteract the digitalis.
你几秒内就会昏迷
You're going to pass out in a few seconds.
你要让心脏继续跳
You need to keep your heart going.
邦德 现在按红钮
Push the red button now, Bond.
- 邦德 按那该死的钮！- 快动手！
- Bond, push the damn button! - Do it now!
- 你还好吗？- 我？
- You okay? - Me?
- 多谢 - 不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
- 现在去医院 - 会去的
- Now get yourself off to a hospital. - I will do.
得等我赢了先
As soon as I've won this game.
你不是真的要回去吧
You're not seriously going back there?
我做梦都想去
I wouldn't dream of it.
押注一百万
Bet. One million.
- 全押 - 跟进 全押
- All in. - Call. All in.
先生们 请摊牌
Gentlemen, showdown, please.
两对 A和7
Two pair. Aces and sevens.
比单张 Q胜
Queen plays. Wins.
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
刚才那手差点搞死我
That last hand, it nearly killed me.
先生们 换完筹码就进入最后阶段
Gentlemen, with this chip exchange, we enter the final phase of the game…
这意味着不能加买筹码了
…which means no more buy-ins.
大盲注是一百万
The big blind is now 1 million dollars.
还有四位玩家
Four players.
请您下注
It's your bet.
- 邦德先生 - 让牌
- Monsieur Bond? - Check.
- 让牌 - 台面上有2千4百万了
- Check. - Twenty-four million in the pot already.
让牌 让牌
Check. And check.
全部让牌
All check.
还有四位玩家
Four players.
- 让牌 - 让牌
- Check. - Check.
全押 6百万
All in. Six million.
押注6百万 全押
Bet. Six million. All in.
5百万全押
Five million. All in.
押注是6百万
Bet is 6 million.
加注
Raise.
1千2百万 单挑
Twelve million. Heads up.
4050万全押
Forty million, 500, 000. All in.
加注 全押
Raise. All in.
那么 我想我要跟进
Well, I think I will call you on that one.
跟进
Call.
桌面上是1亿5千万
One hundred and fifteen million in the pot.
先生们 请摊牌
Gentlemen, showdown, please.
同花 AKQ
Flush. Ace, king, queen.
满堂红 对A和三个8
Full house. Eights full of aces.
更强的满堂红
A higher full house.
对6和三个A
Aces full of sixes.
邦德先生
Monsieur Bond.
黑桃5 7
Five and seven of spades.
同花顺
A straight flush.
从4到8
Four to the eight.
最强牌
The high hand.
邦德先生胜
Monsieur Bond wins.
- 给你的 - 非常感谢
- For you. - Thank you very much.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
- 归你了 - 感激不尽 兄弟
- He's all yours. - Much appreciated, brother.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
庆功会应该准备好了
You know, I think a celebration's in order.
一小时前你差点死掉
You were almost dead an hour ago.
来吧 我饿坏了
Come on, I'm famished.
谢谢
Thank you.
马西斯说美国人与拉西福接触了
Mathis says the Americans have made contact with Le Chiffre.
他们天亮前带走他
They're going to extract him before dawn.
知道吗 我打算叫它「维斯帕」
You know, I think I'll call that a Vesper.
因为它有点苦的回味？
Because of the bitter aftertaste?
不 因为你只要尝过 以后就只想喝它
No. Because once you've tasted it, that's all you want to drink.
- 这台词不错 - 是很好的台词
- I thought that was quite a good line. - lt was a very good line.
但你还在笑
But you're laughing at it.
- 没你笑得厉害 - 哦 那很好
- Not so much it as you. - Well, that's fine then.
我知道那是什么了
I figured out what that is.
是一个阿尔及利亚的相思结
It's an Algerian love knot.
真的？我只是觉得它漂亮
Really? I thought it was just something pretty.
不 你说错了
No, you didn't.
是有人送给你的
Someone gave that to you.
他很幸运
He's a very lucky man.
你转换状态很容易 对吧？
You can switch off so easily, can't you?
杀了那些人你也不放在心上？
It doesn't bother you, killing those people?
如果在意就没法尽心尽责
Well, I wouldn't be very good at my job if it did.
我不相信
I don't believe you.
你可以选择 不是吗？
You've got a choice, you know?
因为任务完成后
Just because you've done something…
并不意味着要继续接任务
…doesn't mean you have to keep doing it.
为什么人总是要提出意见 而不是接受意见呢？
Why is it people who can't take advice always insist on giving it?
你认为我不能接受意见？
You think I can't take my own advice?
我认为有什么东西在驱使你
I think something is driving you.
我想我永远都不会明白
And I think I'll never find out what that is.
马西斯要见我
Mathis needs me.
晚安
Good night.
再次祝贺你
Congratulations again.
马西斯
Mathis.
我恐怕你的朋友马西斯 其实是…
I'm afraid your friend Mathis is really…
我的朋友
…my friend Mathis.
你很爱惜你的身体
You've taken good care of your body.
真是浪费了
Such a waste.
你要知道
You know…
我从没搞明白那些复杂的折磨工具
…I never understood all these elaborate tortures.
弄出男人难以忍受的痛苦
It's the simplest thing…
其实是一件非常容易的事
…to cause more pain than a man can possibly endure.
当然
And of course…
它不光是马上感觉到的巨大痛苦
…it's not only the immediate agony, but the knowledge…
而且你如果不快点招供的话
…that if you do not yield soon enough…
你有可能就不能再做为男人了
…there will be little left to identify you as a man.
唯一的问题就是
The only question remains…
你是否能及时招供
…will you yield in time?
我要那笔钱
I want the money.
林德小姐会给我账号 就算她现在还没给
Miss Lynd will give me the account number, if she hasn't already.
所以我只需要你给我密码
So all I need from you is the password.
密码是什么？
The password, please.
我那里有一点…
I've got a little itch…
痒痒
…down there.
你不介意？
Would you mind?
不！不！不！
No! No! No!
不对 右边一点 往右
No. To the right. To the right. To the right!
你很搞笑 邦德先生
You are a funny man, Mr. Bond.
是的！
Yeah!
是的 是的
Yes, yes, yes.
现在全世界都知道 你死于给我蛋蛋挠痒痒
Now the whole world's gonna know that you died scratching my balls.
我死了？
I died?
- 我死了？- 是的
- I died? - Yes.
因为不管怎样 我都不会给你密码
Because no matter what you do, I'm not gonna give you the password.
于是你的客户会追杀你
Which means your clients will hunt you down…
把你活生生的撕成碎片
…and cut you into pieces of meat while you're still breathing.
如果你杀了我
Because if you kill me…
你就无处可逃
…there'll be nowhere else to hide.
但是你错大了！
But you are so wrong!
即使我宰了你和你的小女朋友
Because even after I slaughtered you and your little girlfriend…
你的人仍然会张开臂膀欢迎我
…your people would still welcome me with open arms…
因为他们需要我所知道的东西
…because they need what I know.
全局情况
The big picture.
把密码给我
Give me the password…
我至少会让她活下来
…and I will at least let her live.
邦德 你快点的话 她可能还是完整的
Bond. Do it soon enough and she might even be in one piece.
你确定不会告诉我 是吗？
You really aren't going to tell me, are you?
是的
No.
那么我想…
So I think…
我会把你不在乎的东西喂给你吃的
…I'll feed you what you seem not to value.
我会拿到钱的
I'll get the money.
告诉他们我会拿到钱的
Tell them I'll get the money.
对组织来说 知道谁可信比钱更重要
Money isn't as valuable to our organization as knowing who to trust.
弗兰西斯卡
Francesco.
维斯帕
Vesper.
不
No.
不是他
Not him.
不是马西斯
Not Mathis.
不
No.
我找医生来
I'll get the doctor.
不是他
Not him.
有何想法？
Any ideas?
- 什么？- 他们为何放你们生路
- What? - Why they left the two of you alive.
她在哪？
Where is she?
睡觉
Sleeping.
我应该要让你喝这个的
Well, I'm supposed to get you to drink this.
只是奇怪…
It's just odd…
其它人都杀了 只留下你和她活着
…killing everyone else but leaving you and her untouched.
有人要告诉我们什么
Almost as if someone was trying to tell us something.
你看到杀手了吗？
Get a look at the killer?
没有
No.
可惜
Shame.
喝完
Drink up.
你还记得什么？
Anything else you remember?
有什么可以帮助我们的？
Anything that can help us?
帮助我们？
Help us?
还是帮助你？
Or help you?
你好
Hello.
你还好吗？
You all right?
忍不住要叫醒你
I can't resist waking you.
我每次叫醒你 你看着我 就像多年未见
Every time I do, you look at me as if you haven't seen me in years.
让我觉得重获新生
It makes me feel reborn.
如果你刚生下来
If you'd just been born…
不是应该赤裸吗？
…wouldn't you be naked?
你可以拥有我
You have me there.
你随时可以拥有我
You can have me anywhere.
可以吗？
I can?
当然 这里 那里 任何你喜欢的地方
Yeah. Here, there, anywhere you like.
这是否意味说你对我有感觉了？
Does this mean that you're warming to me?
是的 可以这么说
Yeah. That's how I would describe it.
不久之前
It's just that not so long ago…
你对我的态度让我…
…I would have described your feelings towards me as…
找不到比「厌恶」更好的词了
I'm trying to think of a better word than "loathing."
我恐怕是个复杂的女人
I'm afraid I'm a complicated woman.
那是因为你害怕某些东西
That is something to be afraid of.
- 你们好 - 哦 真不是时候
- Hello. - Oh, perfect timing.
孟德尔先生 瑞士情形如何？
Monsieur Mendel. How are things in Switzerland?
很抱歉 我不想打搅
My apologies, I do not mean to rush…
不过1亿2千万是很大一笔钱
…but 120 million is a large sum of money.
确实是 你确定没有带巧克力来？
It certainly is. You didn't bring any chocolates with you?
恐怕没有
I'm afraid not.
请输入账号
If you would type in the account number.
还有密码
And now the password.
你来就行了
You can do that.
如果我知道的话
I would if I knew what it was.
维斯帕
V-E-S-P-E-R.
资金已转帐
The funds have been transferred.
抱歉打搅了
Sorry for disturbing you.
- 再见 - 再见 孟德尔先生
- Auf Wiedersehen. - Auf Wiedersehen, Herr Mendel.
知道吗 詹姆斯
You know, James…
就算你只剩下你的微笑和手指
…I just want you to know that if all that was left of you…
你仍然是我所见过的
…was your smile and your little finger…
最像男人的男人
…you'd still be more of a man than anyone I've ever met.
那是因为你知道 我用手指能做什么
That's because you know what I can do with my little finger.
- 我不知道 - 但你急着想知道
- I have no idea. - But you're aching to find out.
你不会接受我的 是吗？
You're not going to let me in there, are you?
你已经又回到你的铠甲里了
You've got your armor back on.
是这样的
That's that.
我没有铠甲了
I have no armor left.
已经被你剥去了
You've stripped it from me.
我所剩下的
Whatever is left of me…
不管我剩下什么
不管我如何
…whatever I am…
我都是你的
…I'm yours.
M几天内不会找我的
I suppose M won't miss me for a couple of days.
她会忙于拷问马西斯
She'll be too busy sweating Mathis.
马西斯？
Mathis?
我告诉过你拉西福的马脚吗？
Remember I told you about Le Chiffre's tell?
马西斯告诉了拉西福
Well, Mathis told Le Chiffre.
所以他能赢我
That's how he wiped me out.
还有追踪器 他们不会轻易知道它的位置
Same goes for the implant. Can't say I'm too sorry about losing that.
因此我爱你
I wonder if that's why I love you.
你爱我吗？
You love me?
爱到辞职跟你去环游世界
Enough to quit and float round the world with you…
直到我们之一找到正当的工作
…until one of us has to find an honest job.
我想那只能是你去找了 因为我不知道什么是正当的工作
But I think that's gonna have to be you. I've no idea what an honest job is.
你认真的吗？
You're serious.
正如你所说
Like you said…
做这种事太久的话
…you do what I do for too long…
都不会剩下什么良心了
…and there won't be any soul left to salvage.
我会带着我仅剩的一点离开的
I'm leaving with what little I have left.
不知道给你够不够？
Is that enough for you?
- 快点 - 不 不
- Come on. - No. No.
不 停下 不 我要去银行了
No, stop it. Stop. I have to get to the bank.
几点了？
What's the time?
我们航海一个月要多少钱？
How much do we need to float for a month?
我有很多钱
I've got plenty.
不 我要支付我的那一半
No, I want to pay for my half of our aimless wanderings.
你不再戴上那条项链了
You stopped wearing the necklace.
是的 到时间了
Yeah. It was time.
时间让你从对某人的记忆中恢复
Time enough to get over someone?
让你意识到有时过去是能遗忘的
To realize sometimes you can forget the past.
但是老板是不能忘记的
Though apparently not your employer.
一个月内回来
Back in one month.
快 我去取钱
Come on. I'll get the money…
你去买给养
…you get supplies.
半小时后在这里会合
I'll see you back here in half an hour.
- 你好 M - 我收到你的消息了
- Hello, M. - I got your note.
是么？
Yes?
我们以后再谈
We'll talk about that later.
现在我们这里有位财政部的可爱先生
Right now I have a lovely man from the Treasury here…
他要知道你是否会把钱存回来
…wondering if you're ever going to deposit the winnings.
真是遗憾 我不知道他们会忘记
That's a shame. I didn't think they'd miss it.
是啊 我告诉他们不要担心
Yes. Well, I told them not to worry.
你今天要把钱存进账户
So you'll be depositing it today.
我正在去银行的路上
On my way to the bank right now.
詹姆斯·邦德 我要同莫德尔先生说话
James Bond for Mr. Mendel.
喂
Hello.
莫德尔先生？我好像无法拿到我账号里的资金
Mr. Mendel? I'm having trouble accessing the funds in my account.
邦德先生 钱被转到…
It was transferred to the account number…
你公司指定的账号上了
…your company gave us, Mr. Bond.
好像资金现在正被取出来
It appears the funds are being withdrawn as we speak.
- 在哪里？- 当然是威尼斯分行
- Where? - The Venice branch, of course.
圣马克广场
St. Mark's Square.
（30分钟后见）
邦德先生 有问题吗？
Is there a problem, Mr. Bond?
我会杀了她！
I'll kill her!
让我来
Allow me.
我很抱歉 詹姆斯
I'm sorry, James.
她有一个男朋友 有法国和阿尔及利亚血统
She had a boyfriend. A French Algerian.
他们很相爱
They were very much in love.
他被拉西福背后的组织绑架
He was kidnapped by the organization behind Le Chiffre.
他们威胁她要合作 否则杀死他
And they blackmailed her, threatening to kill him unless she cooperated.
我们应该发现的
We should've picked up on it…
但我们太专注于我们的敌人
…but sometimes we're so focused on our enemies…
而忘记监视我们的朋友
…we forget to watch our friends.
你怎么样了？
How are you doing?
她留下了她的手机
She left her cell phone.
她肯定知道我要检查的
She must have known I'd check it.
她知道你就是你
She knew you were you.
- 至少让马西斯脱罪 - 不
- Well, at least this clears Mathis. - No.
- 不？- 不
- No? - No.
只是证明她有罪 不是他无辜
We just proved that she's guilty, not that he's innocent.
可能都是内奸 继续拷问他
It could've been a double blind. Keep sweating him.
你谁也不信吗 詹姆斯？
You don't trust anyone, do you, James?
是的
No.
那么你学到教训了
Then you've learnt your lesson.
你赶快回来 我们需要你
Get back as soon as you can. We need you.
会的
Will do.
你如果真需要时间
If you do need time…
为什么我需要时间？
Why should I need more time?
工作完成了 那婊子死了
The job's done, and the bitch is dead.
詹姆斯…
James…
你有没有问过自己 为何当晚你没有死
…did you ever ask yourself why you weren't killed that night?
不是很清楚吗？
Isn't it obvious?
她用钱换了你的命
She made a deal to spare your life in exchange for the money.
我肯定她希望他们放过她
I'm sure she hoped they would let her live.
但她肯定知道自己必死
But she must have known she was going to her death.
现在我们无从知道谁是幕后黑手
And now we'll never know who was behind this.
线索断了
The trail's gone cold.
（给詹姆斯：怀特先生 +3926222431）
- 喂 - 怀特先生
- Hello. - Mr. White?
我们需要谈一谈
We need to talk.
你是谁？
Who is this?
大名是邦德
The name's Bond.
詹姆斯 邦德
James Bond.